You see them on the street. You watch them on TV. You might even vote for one this
fall. You think they're people just like you. You're wrong. Dead wrong.
They Live is a science fiction, action, thriller
film directed by John Carpenter.
A lone drifter stumbles upon a unique pair of sunglasses that reveal aliens are systematically gaining
control of the Earth by masquerading as humans and lulling the public into submission.
John Nada, played by Roddy Piper.
Frank Armitage, played by Keith David.
Holly Thompsen, played by Meg Foster.
Drifter, played by George Buck Flower.
Gilbert, played by Peter Jason.
Street Preacher, played by Raymond St. Jacques.
They Live is a 1988 American science fiction action horror film written, directed, and
scored by John Carpenter, and starring Roddy Piper, Keith David, and Meg Foster.
It was based on the 1963 short story "Eight
O'Clock in the Morning" by Ray Nelson.
Having acquired the film rights to the story prior to the production of They Live, Carpenter used the story as
the basis for the screenplay's structure, which he wrote under the pseudonym "Frank Armitage".
Carpenter has stated that the themes of They Live stemmed from his
dissatisfaction with the economic policies of then-U.S.
President Ronald Reagan, as well as what Carpenter saw as increasing
commercialization in both popular culture and politics.
They Live was a minor success upon release, debuting at
number 1 at the North American box office.
It initially received negative reviews from critics, who lambasted its social commentary, writing, and acting;
however, it later gained a cult following and experienced a significantly more favorable critical reception.
It is now regarded by many as one of Carpenter's best films.
The film has also entered the pop culture lexicon, notably having a lasting
effect on street art (particularly that of Shepard Fairey).
The film explores themes of capitalism, dystopia,
villainess, alien, social commentary.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking and intense.